A Guide to the Stafford County (Va.) Records, 1850-1962
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Stafford County (Va.) Records, 1850-1962
The Library of Virginia
52058
18.35 cu. ft. (19 boxes)
Stafford County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Barcode number 0007696010, 0007696175, and 0007696177 contain Lunacy Papers. Review boxes. There are no restrictions for the rest of the collection.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court papers from Stafford County under the accession number 52058.
Historical Information
Stafford County was named for the English county. It was formed from Westmoreland County in 1664. Part of King George County was added in 1777. The county seat is Stafford.
Many pre–Civil War court records were lost to vandalism by Union troops during the Civil War. A few volumes that record deeds, court orders, and wills exist.
Scope and Content
Stafford County (Va.) Records, 1850-1962, consist of miscellaneous record types. See box content list. Collection includes index listing records found in each box.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Stafford County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records -- Virginia -- Stafford County.
Geographical Names:
Stafford County (Va.) -- History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Bonds (legal records) -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; Civil court cases -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; County government records -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; Criminal court records -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; Fiduciary records -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; Judicial records -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; Local government records -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; Road and bridge records -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Stafford County.
Contents List
- Pigeonholes 1-5, 68, 1856-1924
  Criminal and Civil Cases, Murder Trial of Peter Schooler murdered by William Hunt, (no index page for Pigeonhole 68, misc. jury papers)
- Pigeonholes 6-9, 1865-1903
  Criminal Cases, Estate Inventories, Appraisals, Warrants
- Pigeonholes 10-11, 1899-1903
  Homestead Exemptions, Lunacy Papers, Criminal and Civil Cases
- Pigeonholes 12-13, 1898-1962 circa
  Miscellaneous Court Memos, Fines, Appointments, Warrants, Other Miscellaneous
- Pigeonhole 14, 1882-1937
  Business Licenses and Taxes. Petitions for Roads and Bridges, Purchase of Land for Roads, H.G. Shirley Chairman St. Highway Commission
- Pigeonhole 15, 1866-1901
  Miscellaneous Court Memos, Grand Jury List, Court Cases
- Pigeonholes 16-17, 1866-1903
  Lunacy, State Highway, Criminal and Civil Cases, Wills
- Pigeonholes 18-19, 1853-1908
  Wills, Criminal and Civil Cases
- Pigeonholes 20-24, 1850-1946
  Warrants and Judgments, List of Heirs, Peyton v. Peyton, Lunacy
- Pigeonholes 26-28, 1912-1918
  Payment Records, Road Works, Miscellaneous
- Pigeonholes 33, 36-37, 46-47, 49, 1870-1919
  Miscellaneous, Criminal and Civil Cases, etc.
- Pigeonholes 50-53, 1860-1900
  Pleas of Debt
- Pigeonholes 54-55, 1860-1900
  Pleas of Debt, Miscellaneous Court Notes
- Pigeonholes 56-57, 1860-1900
  Criminal and Civil Cases, Pleas of Debt
- Pigeonholes 98-101, 1902-1932
  Settlements of Estate, Felonies, Divorce, Wills
- Pigeonholes 115-120, 1860-1938
  Deeds, Powers of Attorney, Lists of Land Transfers
- Pigeonholes 255, 257, 1907-1945
  Criminal and Civil Cases, Divorces, Estate Settlements
- Miscellaneous - No Pigeonhole numbers, 1890-1915
  Estate Appraisals and Sales, State Highway Condemnations for Roads
- Index to Pigeonhole files, undated